该过程的下一部分是反射。这就是入射照度反映的地方
The next part of the process is reflectance. That is where the incoming illuminance reflects
一个物体。我们非常熟悉有光泽的表面或镜子反射的能力
off an object. We are very familiar with the ability of shiny surfaces or mirrors to reflect
光。在高中物理学中我们学习了
light. In high school physics we learn about the
来自这样一个表面的反射规则，其中入射角等于角度
rules of reflection from such a surface, where the angle of incidence equals the angle of
反射，我们称之为镜面反射。现在这不是说什么
reflection and we refer to this as specular reflection. Now this is not saying anything
关于反射过程中发生的颜色变化，它只是谈论了
about the color change that occurs during reflection, it is simply talking about the
反射过程的几何形状。我们称之为镜面反射
geometry of the reflection process. We refer to this as specular reflection, which
与镜子的拉丁词有关。我们之前见过WilliamHerschel，他是谁
is related to the Latin word for mirror. We met William Herschel before, who is the guy
谁发现了红外辐射，他在望远镜中制造了大镜子
who discovered infra-red radiation and he made the big mirror in his telescope from
一种被称为窥器金属的金属-它是铜和锡的反射合金
a type of metal that was called speculum metal — it was a reflective alloy of copper and tin and
它曾被用于制造望远镜镜子。
it was used in the old days for making telescope mirrors.
光被物体反射的更真实的模型就是所谓的朗伯（Lambertian）
A more realistic model for the way light is reflected off objects is what is called Lambertian
反射和朗伯反射与镜面反射的不同之处在于传入
reflection, and Lambertian reflection differs from specular reflection in that the incoming
光以各种方向反射。这就是发生的那种反思
light is reflected off in all manner of directions. This is the sort of reflection that occurs
从暗淡或无光泽的表面。有时称为漫反射，它以约翰命名
from a dull or matt surface. Sometimes called diffuse reflection and it is named after Johann
兰伯特，他是18世纪的物理学家。被反射的光的强度
Lambert, who was a physicist in the 1700s. The intensity of the light that is reflected
从表面看，它与反射角有关，而Lambertian则有趣
from the surface is related to the angle of reflection, and what is interesting with Lambertian
反射是它导致亮度对观察者的角度不变
reflection is that it leads to the brightness being invariant to the observer’s angle
观点。现在月亮是兰伯蒂亚的一个很好的例子
of view. Now the moon is a really good example of Lambertian
反射。我们知道月球是一个球体，但是当我们看到它时，它似乎是一个球体
reflection. We know that the moon is a sphere, but when we look at it, it appears to be a
除了陨石坑和海洋之外，相当均匀明亮的圆盘。所以它的原因
fairly uniformly bright disk, apart from the craters and the seas. So the reason that it
即使光被反射，看起来也是均匀明亮的，是成比例的
appears is to be uniformly bright even though the light has been reflected, is proportioned
到角度的cos符号，是我们正在看的区域
to the cos sign of the angle, is that the area of the region that we are looking at
似乎改变了大小。这是一个夸张的例子：我采用了这个特殊的补丁
appears to change in size. Here is an exaggerated example: I take this particular patch of the
月亮和来自那个补丁的大部分光被直接反射，它对应
moon and most of the light from that patch is being reflected directly up, it corresponds
到这样的地方。如果我采取靠近杆子的补丁，很明显
to an area something like this. If I take a patch that is down near the pole it is clearly
对我的视野倾向于倾向于。所以它将拥有其中之一
going to be inclined with respect to my field of view. So it is going to have one of these
光线在这里相关联，所以它将反射较少的光，但区域-
rays down here associated, so it is going to be reflecting less light, but the area—the
这个补丁的表观面积较小，因为我倾斜地看着它。所以如果我考虑一下
apparent area of this patch—is smaller because I am looking at it obliquely. So if I consider
亮度是发射到其表面区域的光的比率，这是
the brightness to be the ratio of the light being emitted to its surface area, this is
对视角不变。所以我们刚看了几何
invariant to the view angle. So we have just looked at the geometry of
反射，射线的方向作为一种功能从表面反射
the reflection, the direction of the rays being reflected form the surface as a function
入射光线。现在让我们谈谈反射如何改变传入的颜色
of the incoming ray. Let’s talk now about how reflection changes the color of incoming
光。在这里我们看到一个红房子砖，这里的情节显示了我们所说的反射率
light. Here we see a red house brick, the plot here shows what we call the reflectance
房子砖;也就是说，从砖块反射的光的比例
of the house brick; that is, the fraction of light that is reflected form the brick
作为波长的函数。这是一个非常复杂的曲线，我们看到有一些
as a function of wavelength. And it is quite a complex curve, we see that there are some
频谱的一部分，它反射大量的光，还有其他
parts of the spectrum where it reflects a large amount of light and there are other
光谱中反射很少光的部分。
parts of the spectrum where it reflects very little light.
右侧图表显示了对频谱可见部分的放大。
The right hand graph shows a zoom into the visible part of the spectrum.
现在我们可以看到红砖在该地区反射的蓝光不是很多
Now we can see that the red brick reflects not very much blue light in the region, say
400至500纳米，但它确实反映了相当多的红光正在下降
400 to 500 nanometers, but it does reflect a fair amount of the red light that is falling
它表示600至700纳米之间的光，这就是为什么它看起来对我们来说是红色的
down, say the light between 600 and 700 nanometers, and that is why it looks red to us, it reflects
更多的红光然后它反射蓝光。所以这是红砖的光谱，不同
more red light then it reflects blue light. So this is the spectrum of a red brick, different
矿物质具有不同的反射光谱，在这里我们可以看到反射光谱
minerals have different reflectance spectrums and here we see the reflectance spectrum for
一些矿物质。如果我们有一台可以测量数字反射率的仪器
a number of minerals. If we have an instrument that can measure the reflectance at a number
不同波长的仪器，可能像光谱仪或超光谱相机，
of different wavelengths, an instrument perhaps like a spectrometer or a hyper spectral camera,
然后我们可以测量这些特定曲线中的一条，我们可以将它与库匹配
then we can measure one of these particular curves and we can match it against a library
已知的矿物质，并用它来识别场景中的矿物质。
of known minerals and use it to identify what minerals are within the scene.
所以回顾一下，入射光，我们称之为照度，它有一个光谱E，
So to recap, incoming light, we refer to as the illuminance and it has got a spectrum E,
它具有波长λ的函数，并且我们有反射率
which has got a function of the wavelength lambda, and we have the reflectance of the
对象本身，我们称之为R，它也是lambda的函数。
object itself which we refer to as R and it is also a function of lambda.
离开苹果的光线，我们称之为苹果的照度，
So the light that leaves the apple, which we refer to as the illuminance of the apple,
我将使用符号L，它也是波长的函数，现在是L
I am going to use the symbol L and it is also a function of the wavelength, now L at any
特定的lambda在相同的lambda乘以R时等于E.
particular lambda is equal to E at that same lambda multiplied by R at that
特别是lambda。这就是离开苹果的光谱，即功能
particular lambda. That is the spectrum of the light that is leaving the apple, the function
入射光的光谱，以及苹果反射率的作用。
of the spectrum of the incoming light, and the function of the reflectance of the apple.